# Sam Protsenko

Software Engineer



# Summary

Software engineer with more than 10 years of professional experience. Main area of expertise is Linux kernel, bootloaders, firmwares and system level user space Embedded programming on ARM-based devices. For the last 5 years has been contributing to open-source projects and involved with upstreaming activity. Has prior experience with cross-platform applications development in C++/Qt, algorithms and electronics. Active open-source community member, mentor, speaker.

## Experience

2018–2020 Team Leader, GlobalLogic, Kyiv.

Supporting the BeagleBoard X15 board and upstreaming work.

- Porting Android to a new board and upstreaming it with a small team: [1]
- Adopting VPN from upstream kernel in AOSP: [2]
- Implementing Android 10 boot sequence: [3]

2012–2018 Software Engineer, GlobalLogic, Kyiv.

Platform development in Linux kernel and bootloaders, upstreaming.

- Implementing and supporting drivers: [4]
- Maintaining boot sequence and fastboot in U-Boot: [5]
- Board bring ups
- Bug fixing (drivers, device tree, bootloader)
- Migrating to new kernel versions
- Implementing XIP boot from NOR flash boot (automotive)
- System boot time optimizations (automotive)

2009–2012 **Software Developer**, AlterEGO, Kramatorsk.

Cross-platform software design and coding.

#### Education

2004–2009 Specialist degree, Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk.

Speciality: Automation of technological processes

# — Computer skills

Languages C, C++, Bash

Projects Linux kernel, U-Boot, Android

Architectures ARM32, AArch64, x86, STM32 (Cortex-M), MSP430

## Languages

Ukrainian Fluent

My native language

Russian Fluent

My native language

English Upper-intermediate

Speaking, reading and writing

## Other Activities

- 2011–Today Maintainer of "INSTEAD" Debian package: [6]
- 2015–Today Active member on StackOverflow (>10k reputation): [7]
  - 2019 Organizer of "Root Linux Conference" in Kyiv: [8]
- 2018–Today Creator and instructor of Linux kernel course: [9]
  - 2017–2019 Speaker at Linaro and GlobalLogic events

### References

- [1] https://android-review.googlesource.com/q/author:protsenko
- [2] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/bkk19/bkk19-414/
- [3] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/san19/san19-217/
- [4] https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/log/?qt=author&q=protsenko
- [5] https://gitlabdenx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/commits/master?search=protsenko
- $[6] \ \, {\tt http://packages.debian.org/sid/instead}$
- [7] https://stackoverflow.com/users/3866447/sam-protsenko
- [8] https://linux.globallogic.com/
- [9] https://github.com/joe-skb7/kernel-lectures